<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>Dev Tracker</title>
		<link>https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/discover/6/</link>
		<description>Guild Wars 2 Forums - Dev Tracker</description>
		<language>en</language>
		<item>
			<title>WTF is Anet doing to WvW?</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145496-wtf-is-anet-doing-to-wvw/?do=findComment&comment=2112661]]>
			</link>
			<description>Hey all! I'd like to make sure I understand and hear more about some of the feedback, so I've
				quoted a few posts below and asked the authors to expand on their thoughts.





				Since the changes to Siege Dampener and Siege Disruptor were in separate updates than the wall/gate
				repair change, are those changes you think should be reverted in general, or do you feel they're no
				longer valid changes alongside the other changes made in the last patch?







				For the lowered stats on the Keep Aura, you mentioned that you feel it was overkill, but didn't say
				that's one of the changes that should be reverted. Do you feel it should be, or do you think it should
				be left alone?





				Can you elaborate on your thoughts a bit? I'm interested in what specific changes you're thinking of and
				why they aren't working for you.





				Since catapults have always been usable on inner and outer walls, are you feeling that the recent
				changes caused that to become an issue or do you feel that it's a long-running problem aside from more
				recent updates? Can you talk more about how it feels like a problem?







				For defensive siege not feeling relevant, do you feel that this is fully related to the most recent
				update?







				As far as the suggestion of making some types of siege easier to destroy - namely catapults and flame
				rams - do you feel that the changes to siege disruptors aid this in any way? Is the increased damage to
				siege from disruptors making a difference in your eyes?







				Are the changes to the keep lords just not very impactful, or do you feel as though they've actually
				worsened them in any way? Have you experienced groups trying to play around the new mechanics at all, or
				you just haven't seen it make an impact in fights where players aren't particularly paying attention to
				it?





				Do you feel as though double team attacks have gotten worse since the recent update, or is it an ongoing
				issue you're calling out?</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 02:50:12 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>When do gem store items, like Mount Skins, recycle again?</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145886-when-do-gem-store-items-like-mount-skins-recycle-again/?do=findComment&comment=2112591]]>
			</link>
			<description>Well first of all, congrats on successfully raising your siege turtle! If you haven't already
				found it, the Siege Turtle Advent Pack is currently available, and the Kaineng Lights set contains some
				siege turtle skins as well.



				To touch on your actual question as well, returning items rotate in and out of the gem store every week,
				with a different category rotating each week. You can check the "What's In Stock" section of our gem
				store blog posts, published every Tuesday on our website.



				The current mount selection will rotate on May 24.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 23:22:27 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>
				<![CDATA[Jade Tech Offensive & Defensive Overcharge Timers Incorrect & Excessive]]>
			</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145464-jade-tech-offensive-defensive-overcharge-timers-incorrect-excessive/?do=findComment&comment=2112557]]>
			</link>
			<description>Hey everyone, I've been keeping an eye on this conversation and talking to several people on
				the team about this change. I want to let you know first that we will be making an adjustment in an
				upcoming build to reduce the cooldown from 90 seconds to 30 seconds.



				To give some context on this change and what led to it, jade tech offensive and defensive protocol
				effects are intended to give players a temporary boost of power at the start of combat, not to maintain
				those boons permanently—which invalidates many skills, traits, relics, and so on.



				We also discovered a bug associated with players having both effects at the same time in a particular
				order, which allowed players to apply the full duration of both boons on demand in certain situations.
				In the April 16 game update, when we corrected the issue, we also adjusted the cooldown to more
				accurately reflect the intent for the jade tech protocol effects.



				However, the change to 90 seconds didn't account for smaller, shorter skirmishes, so while we will not
				reintroduce the bug that prevented the cooldown, we will revert the cooldown to 30 seconds.



				Thank you as always for continuing to share your feedback!</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 21:30:47 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Has Russia disappeared from the list of blocked countries?</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145790-has-russia-disappeared-from-the-list-of-blocked-countries/?do=findComment&comment=2112267]]>
			</link>
			<description>Hello! I can let you know that we do audit and update that list periodically based on various
				factors, including evolving regulations.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 01:18:22 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>World Linking 4/26/2024</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145781-world-linking-4262024/?do=findComment&comment=2111055]]>
			</link>
			<description>Here are the worlds for EU:



				* Augury Rock (FR), Abaddon's Mouth (DE)
				* Aurora Glade (EN), Gunnar's Hold (EN)
				* Baruch Bay (SP)
				* Blacktide (EN), Piken Square (EN)
				* Desolation (EN), Fissure of Woe (EN)
				* Drakkar Lake (DE), Ruins of Surmia (EN)
				* Elona Reach (DE), Underworld (EN)
				* Far Shiverpeaks (EN), Dzagonur (DE)
				* Fort Ranik (FR), Vizunah Square (FR)
				* Gandara (EN), Arborstone (FR)
				* Ring of Fire (EN), Kodash (DE)
				* Riverside (DE), Miller's Sound (DE)
				* Seafarer's Rest (EN), Jade Sea (FR)
				* Vabbi (EN)
				* Whiteside Ridge (EN)



				Here are the worlds for NA:



				* Blackgate, Eredon Terrace
				* Borlis Pass, Northern Shiverpeaks
				* Crystal Desert, Yak's Bend
				* Darkhaven, Stormbluff Isle
				* Dragonbrand, Ferguson's Crossing
				* Fort Aspenwood, Henge of Denravi
				* Gate of Madness, Kaineng
				* Jade Quarry, Anvil Rock
				* Maguuma, Ehmry Bay
				* Sanctum of Rall, Devona's Rest
				* Sea of Sorrows, Sorrow's Furnace
				* Tarnished Coast, Isle of Janthir</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 05:57:23 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>WTF is Anet doing to WvW?</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145496-wtf-is-anet-doing-to-wvw/?do=findComment&comment=2110957]]>
			</link>
			<description>Hey everyone, I want to let you know that several of us have been following and discussing this
				thread for the past week. The team is reviewing the full conversation as well as some smaller, more
				specific details, so they'll probably be hopping into this thread to ask for clarification from some of
				you on various details.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 23:30:44 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>[Suggestions]QoL (Quality of Life) Ideas [Merged]</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145637-suggestionsqol-quality-of-life-ideas-merged/?do=findComment&comment=2110142]]>
			</link>
			<description>This thread is locked but the topic is not closed! Please keep bringing your QOL requests and
				suggestions in the new thread!</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:59:52 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Quality-of-Life Requests and Suggestions (New for 2024)</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145766-quality-of-life-requests-and-suggestions-new-for-2024/?do=findComment&comment=2110141]]>
			</link>
			<description>As we mentioned in our recent blog post, the Guild Wars 2 Live Team has been working for the
				past few years to address player problems and introduce improvements to areas of the game, such as the
				new-player experience, crafting, group encounters, and more.



				Hearing from you, the Guild Wars 2 community, is a big part of this work! I review your QOL requests and
				share them with the Live Team weekly to keep them updated about what's on your mind, and the QOL thread
				has been invaluable for that.



				The previous thread recently passed the 10,000 replies mark and that seems like a good milestone to
				begin a new, less overwhelming thread to collect and track QOL requests. The previous thread can be
				found here for anyone who wants to read past requests.



				Thank you for all of your input on this topic and please keep the QOL requests coming!</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:57:34 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Game Update Notes: April 16, 2024</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145360-game-update-notes-april-16-2024/?do=findComment&comment=2110111]]>
			</link>
			<description>Bug Fix:




				Collecting Wizard's Vault daily objective rewards while inside the Super Adventure Box will now properly
				award PvP and WvW reward track progress.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 23:04:37 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Get In-Game Gold with the "On Wiki of Gold" Project</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145711-get-in-game-gold-with-the-on-wiki-of-gold-project/?do=findComment&comment=2110079]]>
			</link>
			<description>On Wiki of Gold is a player-run project supported by ArenaNet on the official Guild Wars 2
				wiki. Any Guild Wars 2 player can receive in-game gold for contributing to articles listed in the
				project.



				How can I help?



				Log in to your wiki account (or create one), visit the On Wiki of Gold page to see the list of articles
				available for editing, read the guidelines at the top of the page, and create your edit!



				You can improve the nominated article or any article it directly links to. This includes adding missing
				screenshots.
				A nominated article will usually have a suggested edit listed, but that's not required—you can improve
				it in any way you like.







				What if I'm not comfortable editing the wiki?



				You can still contribute missing information or screenshots and get credit by using the "Leave Article
				Feedback" tab that's at the top of every wiki article. Community editors will take care of formatting
				and find the best place for it.







				About the Project



				On Wiki of Gold has been ongoing since September 2016, thanks to project organizer @Delsea.2576 .
				In that time, Guild Wars 2 players have contributed and received gold more than 6,700 times.
				The name is a nod to the On Wings of Gold adventure in Tarir, the Forgotten City.
				Most Guild Wars 2 wiki edits are made without taking part in On Wiki of Gold; the project was created to
				help fill in some of the gaps.



				Our thanks go out to Delsea and all the wiki editors in the Guild Wars 2 community for their work on
				this project!</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 21:10:08 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Game Update Notes: April 16, 2024</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145360-game-update-notes-april-16-2024/?do=findComment&comment=2108395]]>
			</link>
			<description>Bug Fix:




				Fixed an issue that could prevent players from being eligible for some Super Adventure Box Test Zone
				achievements if they completed the requirements before unlocking the Test Zone. The Test Zone
				achievements are no longer locked before the zone is available to a player. Players who are missing an
				achievement they earned will receive it upon entering the Super Adventure Box hub zone.</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 23:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Game Update Notes: April 16, 2024</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145360-game-update-notes-april-16-2024/?do=findComment&comment=2107855]]>
			</link>
			<description>Bug Fixes:




				Essences of Animosity and Certificates of Heroics can now be purchased from Legendary Commander War
				Razor and Legendary Retired Commander Burn Razor in exchange for Testimonies of Jade Heroics.


				Using cosmetic inspection in competitive modes will no longer display players' equipped weapons in the
				character model view window.</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 23:05:39 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Certificate of Heroics cannot be purchased for Testimonies of Jade Heroics [Merged]</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145482-certificate-of-heroics-cannot-be-purchased-for-testimonies-of-jade-heroics-merged/?do=findComment&comment=2107772]]>
			</link>
			<description>Got an update for you: There is a hotfix coming in later today that will address this!
			</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 20:20:23 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>New /unleash emote - trailer appreciation!</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145509-new-unleash-emote-trailer-appreciation/?do=findComment&comment=2107280]]>
			</link>
			<description>I shared this with the person who worked on it--thank you for mentioning it!</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 18:44:45 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Game Update Notes: April 16, 2024</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145360-game-update-notes-april-16-2024/?do=findComment&comment=2106841]]>
			</link>
			<description>Bug Fix:




				Fixed a server crash.</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 01:36:29 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Who else would love a Monster Hunter themed event?</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145218-who-else-would-love-a-monster-hunter-themed-event/?do=findComment&comment=2106677]]>
			</link>
			<description>This is obviously not a promise or even a hint, but all I can think of reading this is
				wandering around Queensdale enjoying the beautiful peaceful scenery, and suddenly hearing the Bazelgeuse
				theme.



				So thank you for the laugh!</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 21:14:19 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>2024 New SAB Decorations</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145460-2024-new-sab-decorations/?do=findComment&comment=2106672]]>
			</link>
			<description>You got them all! They are listed out in the release notes along with the rest of the info
				about this year's updates to SAB!</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 21:05:44 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Super Adventure Festival 2024 Begins Today!</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145449-super-adventure-festival-2024-begins-today/?do=findComment&comment=2106669]]>
			</link>
			<description>There was a brief issue on the website, but it's solved now and all links are working again!
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 21:03:20 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Okay, the front page ad for Super Adventure Box/Festival is cute.</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145463-okay-the-front-page-ad-for-super-adventure-boxfestival-is-cute/?do=findComment&comment=2106657]]>
			</link>
			<description>Passing this on to the relevant person! Thanks for mentioning it--this is a really fun festival
				for that sort of thing!</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 20:45:03 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Next-Level Fashion Wars: Cosmetic Inspect Coming to Guild Wars 2 April 16!</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145438-next-level-fashion-wars-cosmetic-inspect-coming-to-guild-wars-2-april-16/?do=findComment&comment=2106656]]>
			</link>
			<description />
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 20:42:32 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Game Update Notes: April 16, 2024</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145360-game-update-notes-april-16-2024/?do=findComment&comment=2106642]]>
			</link>
			<description>04/16/2024—Late Notes



				General:




				Updated the days remaining in the Wizard's Vault Special Objectives tab.




				Bug Fix:




				Fixed an issue that occurred when interacting with the Searing Cauldron in the Iron Marches.
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 20:27:31 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Super Adventure Festival 2024 Begins Today!</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145449-super-adventure-festival-2024-begins-today/?do=findComment&comment=2106400]]>
			</link>
			<description>Level up with awesome retro-themed rewards during the Super Adventure Festival – starting now
				until May 7!</description>
			<enclosure
				url="https://content.invisioncic.com/a311129/monthly_2024_04/image.jpeg.a7f7fcdb73928defb6d5e921e7f193ee.jpeg"
				length="147034" type="image/jpeg" />
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 17:03:20 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Next-Level Fashion Wars: Cosmetic Inspect Coming to Guild Wars 2 April 16!</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145438-next-level-fashion-wars-cosmetic-inspect-coming-to-guild-wars-2-april-16/?do=findComment&comment=2106053]]>
			</link>
			<description>😄😄😄
				I'm not aware of any plans for a low-poly bird stress ball but I guess I can check.</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:40:04 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Next-Level Fashion Wars: Cosmetic Inspect Coming to Guild Wars 2 April 16!</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145438-next-level-fashion-wars-cosmetic-inspect-coming-to-guild-wars-2-april-16/?do=findComment&comment=2106037]]>
			</link>
			<description>Okay, this is getting circular. Feedback has been noted.



				If you want to discuss other parts of today's news post, please do so. I'd rather not lock the thread.
			</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:25:45 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Next-Level Fashion Wars: Cosmetic Inspect Coming to Guild Wars 2 April 16!</title>
			<link>
			<![CDATA[https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145438-next-level-fashion-wars-cosmetic-inspect-coming-to-guild-wars-2-april-16/?do=findComment&comment=2105856]]>
			</link>
			<description>I'm keeping an eye on feedback for this feature across a number of platforms and languages,
				including this one. So rest assured that this conversation is part of the overall feedback.



				Also: Discussing and disagreeing is fine and great. Name-calling, bickering, and attacking others
				because they don't share your opinion? Not at all fine or great.</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 22:14:07 +0200</pubDate>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
