<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/">

<channel>
	<title>GuildWars2.com</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.guildwars2.com/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
	<link>https://www.guildwars2.com/en</link>
	<description/>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 16:00:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.13</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Get Ready for Brand-New Beetles and Boots in the Gem Store!</title>
		<link>https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/get-ready-for-brand-new-beetles-and-boots-in-the-gem-store/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=news&amp;utm_campaign=rss</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 16:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guild Wars 2 Team]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Launcher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.guildwars2.com/?p=55491</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Winged boots are the perfect look when you're catching air on your roller beetle!</p><p class="more"><a href="https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/get-ready-for-brand-new-beetles-and-boots-in-the-gem-store/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=news&utm_campaign=rss">Read More</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="commerce-items">
<ul>
<p><iframe width="590" height="332" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/pCrmU0PooA0?rel=0&modestbranding=1&showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<h3>Spineshell Roller Beetle Skin</h3>
<p>Race through the desert dunes as the sunset descends on the horizon&mdash;beauty and nature collide. This sturdy beetle is native to the Dzalana Expanse and embodies their incredible strength. The Spineshell Roller Beetle Skin is available for 1,600 gems.</p>
<h3>Raven Greaves Skin</h3>
<p>The Spirits of the Wild beckon you with a melody forged in riddles; follow its beautiful wisdom with these greaves crafted in honor of the Raven spirit. Gear up and match your new boots with the Raven Helm Skin, Raven Mantle Skin, and Raven Gloves Skin. This reverent skin is available for 500 gems.</p>
<p class="screenshot"><a href="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a578cRavenBeetle-BlogAlt.jpg"><img src="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/a578cRavenBeetle-BlogAlt.jpg" alt="A female human character wielding a staff wearing winged metallic boots with a carved raven at the top." width="590" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-50957" /></a></p>
<h3>What&#8217;s in Stock</h3>
<p>In need of a relaxing day? Starting May 3 and continuing for the next few days, select chairs will be 20% off, including the Comfy Cat Chair, Mystic Lotus Chair, Throne of Shadows, Teatime Chair, and many more! Kick back and enjoy a snoozy afternoon.</p>
<p><strong>Returning This Week</strong></p>
<p>Shared Inventory Slots have an amazing 20% discount starting today until May 7. Jump between all of your characters and keep access to your most indispensable items!</p>
<li class="yui3-g">
<div class="yui3-u-1">
<h3>Available Now in the Gem Store!</h3>
<p>Log into <em>Guild Wars 2</em> and press 'O' to access the Black Lion Trading Company for these great offers and more!</p>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Super Adventure Festival 2024 Begins Today</title>
		<link>https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/super-adventure-festival-2024-begins-today/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=news&amp;utm_campaign=rss</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 16:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guild Wars 2 Team]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Launcher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.guildwars2.com/?p=55449</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Explore Moto's virtual world and earn new rewards and achievements!</p><p class="more"><a href="https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/super-adventure-festival-2024-begins-today/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=news&utm_campaign=rss">Read More</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe width="590" height="332" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/V5h5NYjlFXA?rel=0&modestbranding=1&showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>Moto is back in Rata Sum, and so is the Super Adventure Festival! Jump into a virtual world, earn baubles, and exchange them for all sorts of retro-themed rewards. This yearly festival is now live and will be available until May 7. You can check out all the details in the <a target="_blank" href="https://en-forum.guildwars2.com/topic/145360-game-update-notes-april-16-2024">full release notes</a> on our official forums.</p>
<p>Super Adventure Festival is accessible to players of any level. Even if you&#8217;re brand new to the game, you can easily take part in all this festival has to offer! Read on for a quick rundown of the activities you can participate in during this festival and the rewards you can earn.</p>
<h3>Where to Go</h3>
<p>The Super Adventure Festival is located in Rata Sum. Check your in-game mail for an Invitation to the Super Adventure Festival and double-click the item to teleport instantly to the Super Adventure Box Hub. You can also travel to the Magustan Court Waypoint, which is conveniently located right next to the Super Adventure Box in Creator&#8217;s Commons.</p>
<p class="screenshot"><a href="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/55dd2SAB_Environment.08.jpg"><img src="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/55dd2SAB_Environment.08.jpg" alt="Rata Sum decorated with balloons for the Super Adventure Festival." width="590" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-50957" /></a></p>
<h3>What to Do</h3>
<p>When you enter the Super Adventure Box, you will have a different skill set. The new skill bar will help you navigate this different game mode. While you&#8217;re inside the box, you won&#8217;t take damage from falling, and you can&#8217;t use gliders or mounts. But you&#8217;ll find that you&#8217;re much bouncier than you usually are!</p>
<p>There are two complete worlds you can trek through, and two extra gameplay modes that can modify your adventure: Exploration Mode and Tribulation Mode. If you prefer a laid-back adventure, you can enable Exploration Mode, which will give you some assistance traversing jumping puzzles. If you&#8217;re yearning for a punishing challenge, activate Tribulation Mode&#8230;at your peril.</p>
<p>The journey begins in World 1. You are sent on a heroic path to save Princess Miya. Your starting weapon is a stick, but you&#8217;ll be able to buy other combat options and tools from friendly shopkeepers found in the worlds you&#8217;re exploring. Make sure to keep an eye out for little wooden doors!</p>
<p>When you obtain new weapons from merchants inside the Super Adventure Box, they&#8217;ll give you new ways to destroy enemies and objects. You can even use bombs to find hidden rooms packed with baubles.</p>
<p>Bounce your way into a sunny glade, and don&#8217;t forget to fell every enemy on your way! You&#8217;ll need all the baubles you can get your hands on. Every time you get hit by an enemy you will lose a portion of your hearts, so be sure to dodge. When your hearts are empty, you&#8217;ll lose one of your lives. As long as you have lives left, you&#8217;ll revive at the last checkpoint you reached.</p>
<p>If by chance you have no lives left, worry not; simply purchase a Continue Coin from Moto. Just don&#8217;t mind the lava.</p>
<p class="screenshot"><a href="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/99433SAB-2024-blog2.jpg"><img src="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/99433SAB-2024-blog2.jpg" alt="Various heroes wearing the new Powered Shoulders and wielding the Retro-Forged and Golem-Buster weapons." width="590" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-50957" /></a></p>
<h3>Rewards</h3>
<p>Trade 250 baubles to the Super Adventure Box Trader located next to Moto to obtain the festival currency, bauble bubbles! Weapons, armor, utility items, minis, and many more things are available in exchange for bauble bubbles; talk to the trader NPCs just outside the Super Adventure Box or in the Hub.</p>
<p>There are a plethora of new rewards to earn this year. Add a scepter, pistol, sword, and spear to your collection of Retro-Forged weapons, and complete an achievement in the Test Zone to acquire a Mini Green Ooze. Craft new guild hall items to create your own Super Adventure world for your guildmates to enjoy!</p>
<p>Complete the (Annual) Super Adventure Box Nostalgia achievement to earn Golem-Buster weapon skins and the Powered Shoulders, which fit nicely with last year&#8217;s Powered Gloves. You can find them in the Achievement tab of the Hero panel under Festivals.</p>
<p class="screenshot"><a href="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/85c87SAB-2024-blog1.jpg"><img src="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/85c87SAB-2024-blog1.jpg" alt="Various heroes wearing the new Powered Shoulders and wielding the Retro-Forged and Golem-Buster weapons." width="590" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-50957" /></a></p>
<h3>Test Zone</h3>
<p>The Test Zone* has undergone some improvements, and Moto is once again inviting players to explore the new area he&#8217;s been working on! This year, the Test Zone has been expanded, adding new shops, secrets, and achievements for players to uncover. Gourdon the Racing Choya has a new Adventure in the Test Zone as well, and players can unlock a new Magic Bow tool! To visit the Test Zone, pick up the note on the door of the World 3 House in the Hub and follow the instructions. Have fun!</p>
<p><sub>*The Test Zone is presented as is and should not be viewed as World 3 confirmed, either express or implied. Moto, Lord Vanquish, and other residents of the Super Adventure Box will not be held liable for injuries sustained in the Super Adventure Box. Baubles not intended for human (or charr, asura, norn, or sylvari) consumption.</sub></p>
<p class="screenshot"><a href="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/4644fSAB_Test_01.jpg"><img src="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/4644fSAB_Test_01.jpg" alt="Super Adventure Festival Test Zone" width="590" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-50957" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scads of New Items Arrive in Today’s Massive Gem Store Update!</title>
		<link>https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/scads-of-new-items-arrive-in-todays-massive-gem-store-update/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=news&amp;utm_campaign=rss</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 16:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guild Wars 2 Team]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Launcher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.guildwars2.com/?p=55452</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Grab your characters a new outfit, cape, glider, emote, and more.</p><p class="more"><a href="https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/scads-of-new-items-arrive-in-todays-massive-gem-store-update/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=news&utm_campaign=rss">Read More</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="commerce-items">
<ul>
<p><iframe width="590" height="332" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/8-NR-mW8yIQ?rel=0&modestbranding=1&showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<h3>Abyss Hunter Appearance Package</h3>
<p>A whisper follows your every step&mdash;you are a hunter driven by the call of the endless abyss. Stride into the unknown, shrouded in mystery and caressed by the glow of your outfit. Its hue will illuminate your way as you descend&#8230;</p>
<p>The Abyss Hunter Appearance Package contains the Abyss Hunter Outfit, Abyss Hunter Cape Backpack and Glider Combo, a Gold Essence Weapon Choice, and five Monstrous Dye Kits, all for 1,800 gems. The Abyss Hunter Outfit and Abyss Hunter Cape Backpack and Glider Combo can be bought separately for 700 gems each.</p>
<h3>Cosmetic Inspection Celebration</h3>
<p>As we discussed in <a target="_blank" href="https://www.guildwars2.com/news/introducing-our-latest-quality-of-life-feature-cosmetic-inspection">yesterday&#8217;s blog</a>, the cosmetic inspection feature is now live, allowing players to examine the stylish wardrobes of other players to get new ideas for their own fashion. To celebrate this new feature, players can claim five free transmutation charges in the Gem Store, and all dye kits are discounted by 20% until April 23.</p>
<h3>Black Lion Chest Update: Hidden Powers</h3>
<p>Inside each chest, you&#8217;re guaranteed to find a redeemable Black Lion Statuette, a Black Lion Claim Ticket Scrap, and two common items. You also have a chance to find something rarer in the fifth slot, including special items, glyphs, and skins from the Eternal Forged Weapon Collection and the Bright Inquisitor Weapon Collection.</p>
<p><strong>Exclusive Item: &#8220;/Unleash&#8221; Emote Tome</strong></p>
<p>Unlock a new way to express your fighting spirit with the first Black Lion Chest-exclusive emote tome. Dormant inside the deepest part of your soul, a power unlike any other lingers&#8230;the courage to beat all odds! Unleash your bravery with a bang!</p>
<p class="screenshot"><a href="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/1bdd1AbyssHunter-BlogAlt1920X1080.jpg"><img src="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/1bdd1AbyssHunter-BlogAlt1920X1080.jpg" alt="Characters wearing the Abyss Hunter outfit and cape, which are sleek and dark with blue highlights." width="590" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-50957" /></a></p>
<h3>What&#8217;s in Stock</h3>
<p>Adorn your back with our beautiful capes or fancy wings, and make sure to dazzle everyone with your impeccable sense of style! Starting April 19 and continuing for the next few days, select back slot items will be 20% off, including Jora&#8217;s Cape, Celestial Ministry Cape, Forest Archer Pack, Butterfly Wings Backpack Set, and many more!</p>
<p><strong>Returning This Week</strong></p>
<p>Material Storage Expanders, Recharging Teleport to Friend, Black Lion contract boards, and Black Lion Garden Plot Deeds are 20% off starting today until April 23, and Super Adventure Box items are back with a 20% discount until May 7! Don&#8217;t miss out!</p>
<li class="yui3-g">
<div class="yui3-u-1">
<h3>Available Now in the Gem Store!</h3>
<p>Log into <em>Guild Wars 2</em> and press 'O' to access the Black Lion Trading Company for these great offers and more!</p>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing Our Latest Quality-of-Life Feature: Cosmetic Inspection</title>
		<link>https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/introducing-our-latest-quality-of-life-feature-cosmetic-inspection/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=news&amp;utm_campaign=rss</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 13:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guild Wars 2 Team]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Launcher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.guildwars2.com/?p=55442</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The next chapter of the fashion wars begins, plus some other interesting tidbits…</p><p class="more"><a href="https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/introducing-our-latest-quality-of-life-feature-cosmetic-inspection/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=news&utm_campaign=rss">Read More</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello, Tyrians,</p>
<p>As we all know, fashion is the real endgame in <em>Guild&nbsp;Wars&nbsp;2&reg;</em>&mdash;and we have an update coming on April 16 that should help level the playing field for new and aspiring fashionistas.</p>
<p>After countless requests and much anticipation, the stage is finally set for a revolution in Tyria&#8217;s fashion scene with the introduction of cosmetic inspection! In tomorrow&#8217;s release you&#8217;ll find a new option titled &#8220;Inspect Cosmetics&#8221; in the context menu (accessed by right-clicking on another player&#8217;s portrait). Selecting this option will pop open a new panel that allows you to view that player&#8217;s equipped outfit, weapon, and armor cosmetic appearances and their associated dye choices.</p>
<p>This dialog can also be opened by entering the &#8220;/inspect&#8221; chat command with another player targeted. You&#8217;ll notice that some items have been updated with text that outlines how that item can be obtained, and we&#8217;ll be adding even more source descriptions in coming releases.</p>
<p><iframe width="590" height="332" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/G0GfoyoQSe4?rel=0&modestbranding=1&showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>It&#8217;s important to note that this is a cosmetics-focused feature. Inspection does not give players information about the rarity or attribute selection of any item, nor does it provide details about equipped infusions, runes, or sigils. Additionally, to preserve competitive integrity in the PvP and WvW game modes, cosmetic inspection cannot be used to determine what weapons enemy players have equipped.</p>
<h3>Life Gets Better</h3>
<p>The cosmetic inspection feature is the latest quality-of-life improvement from the <em>Guild&nbsp;Wars&nbsp;2</em> Live Team. Their mandate over the past few years has been to address player problems and introduce improvements to areas of the game, such as the new-player experience, crafting, and group encounters. Here are some of their accomplishments in service of that goal:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Legendary Armory</li>
<li>The Wizard&#8217;s Vault</li>
<li>Reintroduction of Living World Season 1</li>
<li>New and refreshed Bonus Week events</li>
<li>Allied player visual-effect toggle</li>
<li>Granular postprocessing options</li>
<li>Character selection-screen background customization</li>
<li>Progress bars for meta-achievements</li>
<li>Guild hall game-mode options</li>
<li>Filtering options in the Trading Post for skins you have unlocked</li>
<li>Recent rework of gobbler items</li>
</ul>
<p>Sometimes our work on this front is less obvious or impacts the community in a roundabout way&mdash;like the work we&#8217;re doing to improve our development pipeline and tools and the work we&#8217;re doing to improve the technology that underlies <em>Guild&nbsp;Wars&nbsp;2</em>, such as our engine.</p>
<p>Our commitment to not just maintaining but enhancing <em>Guild&nbsp;Wars&nbsp;2</em> is rooted in our belief that for a game to remain vibrant and engaging, it must evolve. The shift to DirectX11 was a milestone that marked just the beginning of our journey toward technological enhancement. This move was not simply about keeping up with the times; it was a declaration of our dedication to providing our players with an experience that continuously improves.</p>
<p>Thanks to DX11, we&#8217;ve been able to increase the number of armature bones and lighting objects for new models and environments, build full 360-degree skyboxes, and begin using vertex animation (or point-level animation). One of the engine improvements we&#8217;re working on right now is an upgrade to BC7 texture compression, a significant jump over the technology that we&#8217;ve been leveraging since the launch of the game. This will improve the clarity and fidelity of in-development and future textures, most notably for weapons, visual effects, environments, and creatures. In the longer term, we&#8217;ll be evaluating the feasibility of upgrading existing, already-shipped textures to BC7 compression, but there are some technical hurdles for us to overcome before we commit. </p>
<p>These enhancements not only pave the way for better visuals and smoother gameplay but also ensure that <em>Guild&nbsp;Wars&nbsp;2</em> remains a competitive, dynamic world that evolves with its community. We&#8217;ll have more developments to share on this front as the team continues their work.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s a sneak peek at a new location from the fifth <em>Guild&nbsp;Wars&nbsp;2</em> expansion&mdash;shipping later this year:</p>
<p class="screenshot"><a href="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ce36fEXenvirpreview1920X1080.jpg"><img src="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/ce36fEXenvirpreview1920X1080.jpg" alt="A landscape screenshot from the fifth expansion featuring a beautiful sunlit path through a forest." width="590" height="332" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-50935" /></a></p>
<p>Thanks for reading! I&#8217;ll see you in the game.</p>
<p>&mdash;Josh Davis, Game Director</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Succumb to Your Midnight Urges with the Devil-Rending Dagger Skin</title>
		<link>https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/succumb-to-your-midnight-urges-with-the-devil-rending-dagger-skin/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=news&amp;utm_campaign=rss</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 16:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guild Wars 2 Team]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Launcher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.guildwars2.com/?p=55423</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A new skin to add to your Devil-Rending weapon set . If your midnight urges involve cake, it can cut that, too!</p><p class="more"><a href="https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/succumb-to-your-midnight-urges-with-the-devil-rending-dagger-skin/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=news&utm_campaign=rss">Read More</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="commerce-items">
<ul>
<p><iframe width="590" height="332" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/bd2t0ryNWlA?rel=0&modestbranding=1&showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<h3>Devil-Rending Dagger Skin</h3>
<p>As the moon rises high above Divinity&#8217;s Reach, the streets carry a familiar scent&mdash;blood and fear. This dagger is enchanted with sanguine magic, allowing its wielder to easily stalk their prey. The Devil-Rending Dagger is the ideal deadly companion to the Devil-Rending Axe Skin, Devil-Rending Greataxe Hammer Skin, and Devil-Rending Cape. This harrowing skin is available now for 600 gems.</p>
<h3>What&#8217;s in Stock</h3>
<p>Starting April 12 and continuing for the next few days, select gathering tools will be 20% off, including the Thunderstrike Harvesting Tool, Earthshaker Mining Tool, Firestorm Logging Tool, and many more! Gather all that you need fashionably.</p>
<p><strong>Returning This Week</strong></p>
<p>Salvage everything you want or add new templates to your account with these incredible discounts: until April 16, the Copper-Fed Salvage-o-Matic, Silver-Fed Salvage-o-Matic, Runecrafter&#8217;s Salvage-o-Matic, and Equipment Template Expansions are 20% off, and Build Template Expansions are 40% off.</p>
<p class="screenshot"><a href="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/0349eMTX-Devil-Rending-BlogAlt.jpg"><img src="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/0349eMTX-Devil-Rending-BlogAlt.jpg" alt="A female human character in dark armor brandishes blood-red daggers coursing with crimson magic." width="590" height="332" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-50935" /></a></p>
<li class="yui3-g">
<div class="yui3-u-1">
<h3>Available Now in the Gem Store!</h3>
<p>Log into <em>Guild Wars 2</em> and press 'O' to access the Black Lion Trading Company for these great offers and more!</p>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Preorder the Guild Wars 2: Secrets of the Obscure Vinyl Soundtrack</title>
		<link>https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/preorder-the-guild-wars-2-secrets-of-the-obscure-vinyl-soundtrack/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=news&amp;utm_campaign=rss</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 17:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guild Wars 2 Team]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Launcher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.guildwars2.com/?p=55411</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Treat yourself to twenty-four otherworldly tracks, releasing in Q2 2024!</p><p class="more"><a href="https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/preorder-the-guild-wars-2-secrets-of-the-obscure-vinyl-soundtrack/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=news&utm_campaign=rss">Read More</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="screenshot"><a href="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/b612bSotO-Vinyl_1920x1080.png"><img src="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/b612bSotO-Vinyl_1920x1080.png" alt="The Secrets of the Obscure Vinyl Soundtrack" width="590" height="332" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-50935" /></a></p>
<p>Today we&#8217;re thrilled to announce an upcoming vinyl edition soundtrack for <em>Guild&nbsp;Wars&nbsp;2&reg;:&nbsp;Secrets&nbsp;of&nbsp;the&nbsp;Obscure&trade;</em>. This double LP set will be created by Materia Music and released in Q2 of 2024. You can preorder it <a target="_blank" href="https://materia.store/products/guild-wars-2-secrets-of-the-obscure-original-game-soundtrack-2xlp-vinyl-record">here</a> for $39.99 USD. If you&#8217;re in the EU, preorders are available <a target="_blank" href="https://blackscreenrecords.com/products/guild-wars-2-secrets-of-the-obscure?variant=45247833080074">here</a>.</p>
<p>The soundtrack will feature 24 tracks composed by Maclaine Diemer, Bryan Atkinson, and others. The track selections reflect the otherworldly nature of <em>Guild&nbsp;Wars&nbsp;2:&nbsp;Secrets&nbsp;of&nbsp;the&nbsp;Obscure&#8217;s</em> cross-dimensional locations and antagonists. From the Wizard&#8217;s Tower to Nayos, the Realm of Dreams, this new lineup of songs is punctuated by dark, heavy music with pounding drums, distorted textures, and snarling vocals, all swirling together in chaotic dissonance.</p>
<p>Additionally, we&#8217;ll be partnering with Materia Music to make the majority of the <em>Guild&nbsp;Wars&nbsp;2</em> soundtrack available on most major streaming platforms, including Spotify, Apple Music, Bandcamp, Amazon, and YouTube.</p>
<p>The track names and composers for the vinyl edition soundtrack are as follows:</p>
<p><strong>Side A&mdash;16:51</strong><br />
1 &#8211; &#8220;Secrets of the Obscure&#8221; (Maclaine Diemer)<br />
2 &#8211; &#8220;A Fractured Horizon&#8221; (Maclaine Diemer)<br />
3 &#8211; &#8220;Isgarren the Curator&#8221; (Jarryd Elias)<br />
4 &#8211; &#8220;Strangers Masked in Shadow&#8221; (Bryan Atkinson)<br />
5 &#8211; &#8220;Whispers of the Misplaced&#8221; (Maclaine Diemer)<br />
6 &#8211; &#8220;Memories Forgotten&#8221; (Maclaine Diemer)<br />
7 &#8211; &#8220;The Beast Emerges&#8221; (Maclaine Diemer and Bobby Rose)			</p>
<p><strong>Side B&mdash;18:34</strong><br />
1 &#8211; &#8220;Amnytas in Peril&#8221; (Maclaine Diemer)<br />
2 &#8211; &#8220;Flesh and Fire&#8221; (Bobby Brader)<br />
3 &#8211; &#8220;Curious Allies&#8221; (Maclaine Diemer)<br />
4 &#8211; &#8220;The Kryptis&#8221; (Bryan Atkinson)<br />
5 &#8211; &#8220;The Wizards&#8221; (Maclaine Diemer)<br />
6 &#8211; &#8220;These Ancient Halls&#8221; (Maclaine Diemer)<br />
7 &#8211; &#8220;Courage and Regret&#8221; (Bryan Atkinson)<br />
8 &#8211; &#8220;Otherworldly Threats&#8221; (Bobby Rose)<br />
9 &#8211; &#8220;Nayos&#8221; (Bryan Atkinson)	</p>
<p><strong>Side C&mdash;16:21</strong><br />
1 &#8211; &#8220;Malaise&#8221; (Jaimee Jimin Park)<br />
2 &#8211; &#8220;Peitha&#8217;s Flame&#8221; (Maclaine Diemer)<br />
3 &#8211; &#8220;To Fell a King&#8221; (Maclaine Diemer)<br />
4 &#8211; &#8220;Eparch&#8217;s Finest&#8221; (Bobby Rose and Jarryd Elias)<br />
5 &#8211; &#8220;Might of the Cosmos&#8221; (Michael Paraskevas)<br />
6 &#8211; &#8220;An Army of Avarice&#8221; (Bobby Brader)<br />
7 &#8211; &#8220;The Bloodied Lord&#8221; (Bryan Atkinson)<br />
8 &#8211; &#8220;A Promise&#8221; (Bryan Atkinson)	</p>
<p><strong>Side D&mdash;16:45</strong><br />
1 &#8211; &#8220;For the Ward!&#8221; (Bryan Atkinson)<br />
2 &#8211; &#8220;The Realm of Dreams&#8221; (Bryan Atkinson)<br />
3 &#8211; &#8220;Drum of the Hunt&#8221; (Bryan Atkinson)<br />
4 &#8211; &#8220;Vertigo&#8221; (Bryan Atkinson)<br />
5 &#8211; &#8220;Maelstrom of Brawn&#8221; (Bryan Atkinson)<br />
6 &#8211; &#8220;From Dusk&#8221; (Bryan Atkinson)<br />
7 &#8211; &#8220;Marching Orders&#8221; (Bryan Atkinson)<br />
8 &#8211; &#8220;The King&#8217;s Paragon&#8221; (Bryan Atkinson)</p>
<p><strong>TOTAL&mdash;1:08:32</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Berrylicious Dyes Arrive Today!</title>
		<link>https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/new-berrylicious-dyes-arrive-today/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=news&amp;utm_campaign=rss</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 16:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guild Wars 2 Team]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Launcher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.guildwars2.com/?p=55404</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We've also got sweet discounts; unlock new armor skins and dye them with your favorite colors!</p><p class="more"><a href="https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/new-berrylicious-dyes-arrive-today/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=news&utm_campaign=rss">Read More</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="commerce-items">
<ul>
<p class="screenshot"><a href="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/e665fgw2-0402-mtx-smooth-berry-dye-1920x1080.jpg"><img src="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/e665fgw2-0402-mtx-smooth-berry-dye-1920x1080.jpg" alt="A human female character is shown six times wearing the same armor with different dyes: pink, blue, green, yellow, cream, and gray." width="590" height="332" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-50935" /></a></p>
<h3>Smooth Berry Dye Kit</h3>
<p>The sweet aroma of spring arrives with delightful shades. The Black Lion Trading Company partnered with the Grove&#8217;s sylvari to bring you these lovely vibrant colors. Every kit contains one random dye from a pool of 25 colors that includes the following new exclusive dyes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Afternoon Wine Dye</li>
<li>Deep Sea Dye</li>
<li>Light Viridian Dye</li>
<li>Mustard Dye</li>
<li>Pastel Lavender Dye</li>
<li>Slate Dye</li>
</ul>
<p>All unlocked dyes can be accessed by any character on your account and used an unlimited number of times. Dyes can be used to change the appearance of your armor skins, outfits, skiffs, and mounts. Enjoy the new season to the fullest!</p>
<h3>What&#8217;s in Stock</h3>
<p>Starting April 5 and continuing for the next few days, select armor sets will be 20% off. Dazzle your foes and friends alike with these incredible armor sets: Strider&#8217;s Medium Armor Skin, Aetherblade Heavy Armor Skin, Aetherblade Medium Armor Skin, Aetherblade Light Armor Skin, Incarnate Light Armor Skin, and Rampart Heavy Armor Skin. Try out our new dyes on these discounted ensembles!</p>
<p><strong>Returning This Week</strong></p>
<p>It&#8217;s always a good day for a complete makeover! Change your characters or adjust their looks with our amazing discounts. Transmutation Charges, Total Makeover Kits, Self-Style Hair Kits, and Name Change Contracts are 20% off starting today until April 9.</p>
<li class="yui3-g">
<div class="yui3-u-1">
<h3>Available Now in the Gem Store!</h3>
<p>Log into <em>Guild Wars 2</em> and press 'O' to access the Black Lion Trading Company for these great offers and more!</p>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Model the Beauty of Statues with the Shattered Stone Wings Backpack and Glider Combo</title>
		<link>https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/model-the-beauty-of-statues-with-the-shattered-stone-wings-backpack-and-glider-combo/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=news&amp;utm_campaign=rss</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 16:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guild Wars 2 Team]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Launcher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.guildwars2.com/?p=55393</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You will blend in perfectly in the Museum of Curiosities.</p><p class="more"><a href="https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/model-the-beauty-of-statues-with-the-shattered-stone-wings-backpack-and-glider-combo/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=news&utm_campaign=rss">Read More</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="commerce-items">
<ul>
<p><iframe width="590" height="332" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/i5TmnjEpgtg?rel=0&modestbranding=1&showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<h3>Shattered Stone Wings Backpack and Glider Combo</h3>
<p>These beautiful wings were inspired by ancient dwarven stonecraft and statuary devoted to the human gods; polished rock and arcane magic are combined to create a magnificent piece of art. </p>
<h3>Travel with Friends Package</h3>
<p>Make sure to check out our amazing discounted package! The Travel with Friends Package is still available for 2,000 gems until April 2 and includes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Recharging Teleport to Friend</li>
<li>Black Lion Hero Point Scroll</li>
<li>Waypoint Unlock Box</li>
<li>Black Lion Outfit Voucher</li>
</ul>
<p class="screenshot"><a href="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/e5307MTX-ShatteredWings-06.jpg"><img src="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/e5307MTX-ShatteredWings-06.jpg" alt="A top-down view of two characters gliding with magical pink and blue wings made of shattered stone." width="590" height="332" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-50935" /></a></p>
<h3>What&#8217;s in Stock</h3>
<p>Starting March 29 and continuing for the next few days, select gliders and glider combos will be 20% off. Don&#8217;t miss the perfect time to fly in style with the following backpack and glider combos: Scaled Dragon Wings, Shrine Guardian, Nightspeaker Wings, Skeletal Wings, Venombite Wings, and many more!</p>
<h3>March Sales</h3>
<p>As part of our March sales, many account upgrades such as Bank Tab Expansions, Bag Slot Expansions, and Character Slot Expansions are 20% off starting today until April 2. If you need to boost your account, this is perfect for you!</p>
<li class="yui3-g">
<div class="yui3-u-1">
<h3>Available Now in the Gem Store!</h3>
<p>Log into <em>Guild Wars 2</em> and press 'O' to access the Black Lion Trading Company for these great offers and more!</p>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WvW World Restructuring Beta Feedback and Future</title>
		<link>https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/wvw-world-restructuring-beta-feedback-and-future/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=news&amp;utm_campaign=rss</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guild Wars 2 Team]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Launcher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.guildwars2.com/?p=55347</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Learn more about the feedback from the last WvW World Restructuring Beta and what's next!</p><p class="more"><a href="https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/wvw-world-restructuring-beta-feedback-and-future/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=news&utm_campaign=rss">Read More</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello, Mist warriors,</p>
<p>This is Cecil Armstrong, the Competitive Producer for <em>Guild&nbsp;Wars&nbsp;2</em>. We recently completed a World Restructuring beta event, which ran from January 12 to February 2, so let&#8217;s talk about it!</p>
<p>We&#8217;re pretty happy with the results and data gathering provided by this beta: uncovering some startup data errors, increased queue issues, and some beta-specific reset and UI errors. In addition, we gathered great feedback from community members about their experiences and have some good areas for improvement identified. We&#8217;ve already set to work on those fixes and improvements, so let&#8217;s get into some of the details.</p>
<p class="screenshot"><a href="https://d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/c2eb7gw067.jpg"><img src="https://d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/c2eb7gw067.jpg" alt="The entrance to a World vs World Tower" width="590" height="332" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-50935" /></a></p>
<h3>The Issues</h3>
<h4>Team Placement (or &#8220;Where am I, and who are all these people?&#8221;)</h4>
<p>We uncovered several individually small issues that compounded upon one another and led to incorrect team placement. First, during the EU reset at the start of the beta, we discovered that our servers had failed to read the new team-creation data and fell back to its last known good data: the teams from the last beta. We identified the issue pretty much immediately and restarted the matchup with the correct data. Unfortunately, some players were presented with the option to select their team when the wrong data was active, and that choice prevented them from being fixed in that reset. Ultimately, our engineers came up with a clever solution that allowed us to identify the affected players and fix them programmatically, but we couldn&#8217;t get it done until early evening Pacific Time, so most of our EU players had already logged off for the night.</p>
<p>After resolving that, we could dig into the still-unknown reports. We identified a trend of people who told us they selected their guild close to the lockout deadline and started exploring that thread, revealing our second major issue. The analytics that track guild selection had an error and stopped reporting during the night before the lockout, effectively preventing any selection from making it to the server for an extra day. This was an easy fix once it was spotted, and now we&#8217;ve got some safeguards in place to spot the issue if it were to occur again.</p>
<p>The rest of the issues in this category occurred very rarely, and some are still being investigated, but we also caught a couple of places where the system was working as expected but felt broken. The first is in the case of an inactive WvW guild. Our system has a method for removing guilds and players from the team-creation data if they don&#8217;t participate in WvW for an extended period. Normally, this won&#8217;t affect you if you have a WvW guild selected, as it is very likely someone else that selected that guild has played WvW recently. If no one with the guild selected has played recently, everyone in it gets sorted as a solo player. We are looking into solutions for this.</p>
<p>The other edge case we saw affected players who had transferred worlds to a different region. If you normally play in NA but had transferred to EU during the lockout, you would be sorted into a team on EU. If you then transferred back to NA, you wouldn&#8217;t have been kept with your WvW guild.</p>
<p>The combination of all these issues meant a lot of players were not kept with their guilds as expected, especially in the first team creation. I want to give a huge shoutout and thanks to Rubi, Roy, and the amazing members of our Customer Service team, who spent a lot of time getting players manually moved to the right teams to minimize the impact of these issues. This is the first beta for which we had a proper solution for manually changing teams, and we certainly put it through some rigorous live testing.</p>
<h4>The Queues</h4>
<p>The dreaded &#8220;queue issue&#8221; or &#8220;Map Is Full&#8221; error struck again during this beta. With the increased population due to the very popular WvW Rush and World Restructuring beta, we saw occurrences and reports of these issues skyrocket.</p>
<p>While this is sort of a known quantity and ongoing investigation in WvW, we did find some new variations of this issue that are specific to the World Restructuring system. The team is exploring why that might be and seeing if it can inform the larger queue-issue investigation as well.</p>
<h4>UI (or &#8220;What you see is what you sometimes get.&#8221;)</h4>
<p>Beta resets have had some odd UI errors, and while we solved many of them, there were a couple that still affected us this time around. Notable reset errors were:</p>
<ul>
<li>Team names could be incorrect on the WvW Mist War panel</li>
<li>Players could be unable to join WvW via the UI or portals</li>
</ul>
<p>Thankfully, these have a simple workaround and are fixed by relogging, but they still led to reset frustration for lots of players. We also discovered an issue in which players that had set themselves to invisible status would not see the proper UI for their WvW guilds. While this issue was visual only and the server was still getting the proper data, it likely caused people to be misplaced in team creation due to the confusion. Luckily, all these errors have somewhat similar root causes, and we have fixes prepared for them.</p>
<p class="screenshot"><a href="https://d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/906cdgw066.jpg"><img src="https://d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/906cdgw066.jpg" alt="Looking from a distance at the entrance to a World vs World Tower" width="590" height="332" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-50935" /></a></p>
<h3>The Feedback</h3>
<p>Despite the issues, the beta was very successful in many ways, giving us tons of data and great player feedback. Thank you all for sharing your experiences with us to help us improve the World Restructuring system! I want to quickly address some of the major feedback topics.</p>
<h4>Some Matchups and Time Zones Felt Unbalanced/Unorganized</h4>
<p>This was a mixed experience. There has been a lot of discussion about the balance of specific matchups, time zone coverage, and the distribution of experienced commanders (especially open tags). I am very glad that we received so much feedback in this area, as it was the primary goal of this beta. Our new team-creation algorithm was utilized for the first time, and the new criteria are working as expected.</p>
<p>The goal of this system is to create the most engaging matches possible, ensuring there is a good balance of player and commander activity throughout the matchups and across time zones.  We certainly have improvements to make with how our criteria are used to create balanced teams, but initial data and feedback shows us moving in a good direction.</p>
<h4>Language Barriers</h4>
<p>Many players in our EU community experienced issues communicating with their teammates due to the heavy mixing of international guilds and players. With communication being so critical to a good WvW experience, this is a major area of improvement for us. This is challenging to solve without breaking down the balance aspects of the team-creation algorithm. We don&#8217;t have a timeline or solution nailed down for this yet, but we are investigating ways to mitigate the issue.</p>
<h4>Loss of Server Communities</h4>
<p>Several players have expressed a feeling of loss of community with the World Restructuring system. While we understand that this departure from the longstanding WvW server system will have some negative impacts, World Restructuring provides a regular redistribution of players that is critical to the long-term health and balance of the game mode. We are aiming to provide tools and options for you to create and maintain robust communities within the new structure.</p>
<h4>Queues Are Bad</h4>
<p>We hear you! This was a major issue for some teams. During this first week, this was heavily impacted by a population surge from the WvW Rush event, but even in later weeks we could see some significant queue times on certain teams. We&#8217;re looking into ways to reduce queue pressure in prime-time slots while protecting balance in lower population times.</p>
<p>Many players have also pointed out that long queues led to an increase in AFK players; a vicious cycle. We are investigating better ways to clear inactive players from the maps to reduce this inflated pressure on queues.</p>
<p>Of course, both of these issues were also made worse (and significantly more frustrating) by the &#8220;Map Is Full&#8221; errors we discussed above, and that investigation is a top priority for us.</p>
<h4>Fun Facts</h4>
<p>During the World Restructuring beta, I was paying special attention to commanders and saw a lot of extra people tagging up!</p>
<ul>
<li>Unique Commanders: 6,236</li>
<li>Commanders were tagged for an average of 4.7 hours during the beta</li>
<li>Average weekly commanding hours increased by approximately 26% during the beta</li>
</ul>
<p>Earlier this year, an issue caused us to disable gliding in WvW for a period, which ended up being a sort of impromptu rules change test. Many of our players certainly felt the impact, as you&#8217;ll see below.</p>
<ul>
<li>35,546 players died of fall damage while gliding was disabled</li>
<li>This averaged 5,359 falling deaths per day; a 94% increase over the normal daily average</li>
</ul>
<p class="screenshot"><a href="https://d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/989cegw059.jpg"><img src="https://d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/989cegw059.jpg" alt="Airship hovering over a World vs World Location" width="590" height="332" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-50935" /></a></p>
<h3>The Future</h3>
<p>With this beta wrapped up and lots of work yet to come, we want to talk a little about our future plans.</p>
<h4>Better Information in More Places</h4>
<p>This is a system with lots of moving parts, data, deadlines, and player input. In an effort to make that information more accessible and apparent, we&#8217;re planning several UI and API improvements. We don&#8217;t have a definite timeline on these yet, but we will share updates as we have them.</p>
<ul>
<li>UI
<ul>
<li>Adding Next Team Creation and Next Lockout Deadline to guild/WvW panels</li>
<li>Adding guild roster indicators for players who have chosen the currently viewed guild as their WvW guild</li>
<li>Making the WvW Team Selection panel information visible but inactive when you have an assigned team, allowing players to see what teams their contacts and guilds are on</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>API
<ul>
<li>Adding Next Team Creation times for each region</li>
<li>Adding Next Lockout Deadline</li>
<li>Adding WvW guilds&#8217; assigned teams</li>
<li>Adding WvW guilds&#8217; next team
<ul>
<li>Similar to our World Linking forum posts, this would allow guilds to know what team they will be assigned at reset as soon as the team-creation data reaches the server</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Adding an API key option for a player&#8217;s selected WvW guild</li>
<li>Adding an API key option for a player&#8217;s assigned team / next team</li>
</ul>
</ul>
<h4>Sixth Guild Slot</h4>
<p>Many players were frustrated by the feeling of &#8220;losing&#8221; a guild slot to properly organize in the World Restructuring system. We always want to encourage players to build long-lasting and meaningful communities in our game, and this made that more difficult. To remedy that, we have decided to add a sixth guild slot when World Restructuring is turned on full-time. This new guild slot will have all normal guild functions, and it will be available to all players, regardless of their WvW participation.</p>
<h4>Region Transfers</h4>
<p>During the beta, we got quite a few questions about the future of world and region transfers with the removal of home worlds. We wanted to let you know that region transfer functionality will still be available via an updated character selection interface. In addition, we will be setting the gem cost to transfer regions to a flat 500 gems, as we no longer need to have variable costs based on world populations.</p>
<h4>Next Beta</h4>
<p>While the beta was mostly a major success for the team, we are concerned about the new version of the queue issue we&#8217;ve discovered, particularly the evidence that World Restructuring is worsening it. With the &#8220;Map Is Full&#8221; error being such an extremely negative player experience, we aren&#8217;t comfortable enabling the system full-time before we resolve it. Investigating this issue is the number-one priority for the World Restructuring team, but we don&#8217;t have an expected timeline to solve it right now. We will share more information on this issue when we can.</p>
<p>Once we find a solution to this queue issue, we&#8217;ll have a clearer picture of what the next step is for turning World Restructuring on full-time. Ideally, the next time we turn on World Restructuring, it will stay on.</p>
<h4>Thanks for Participating!</h4>
<p>Your involvement in our World Restructuring beta events has given us the ability to test and tune the system to support the future of WvW. We&#8217;ve got lots of exciting stuff coming and lots of hard work ahead, but we couldn&#8217;t have gotten here without your participation and support.</p>
<p>For now, I&#8217;ll leave you with a quick reminder of our current priorities. The Future Goals section below specifically references things that we know we want to do but could be deprioritized or significantly delayed as other important issues come up.</p>
<ul>
<li>Top Priority
<ul>
<li>New World Restructuring &#8220;Map Is Full&#8221; error investigation</li>
<li>Adding Next Lockout Deadline timer to in-game UI</li>
<li>Add 6th Guild Slot</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Future Goals (No Timeline)
<ul>
<li>API integrations for WvW and World Restructuring information</li>
<li>Additional guild &#038; WvW interface improvements</li>
<li>Better mixed-language team experience</li>
<li>Improved detection of inactive players</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Whimsical Skiffs and High-Tech Shields in Today’s Gem Store Update!</title>
		<link>https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/whimsical-skiffs-and-high-tech-shields-in-todays-gem-store-update/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=news&amp;utm_campaign=rss</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 16:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The Guild Wars 2 Team]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home Page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Launcher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.guildwars2.com/?p=55361</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Whether you're looking for protection or playfulness, we've got new toys for you.</p><p class="more"><a href="https://www.guildwars2.com/en/news/whimsical-skiffs-and-high-tech-shields-in-todays-gem-store-update/?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=news&utm_campaign=rss">Read More</a></p>]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="commerce-items">
<ul>
<p><iframe width="590" height="332" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/06icC-NpTIc?rel=0&modestbranding=1&showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<h3>Synergetics Energized Shield Skin</h3>
<p>Protect yourself with a sophisticated, high-tech shield. The College of Synergetics designed this weapon with a sleek edge and a powerful holographic barrier to keep you and your allies safe in any perilous situation.</p>
<h3>Travel with Friends Package</h3>
<p>As mentioned in our March sales blog, throughout the month we will be releasing special, valuable packages for you to expand your account. The Travel with Friends Package is available for 2,000 gems until April 2 and includes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Recharging Teleport to Friend</li>
<li>Black Lion Hero Point Scroll</li>
<li>Waypoint Unlock Box</li>
<li>Black Lion Outfit Voucher</li>
</ul>
<p class="screenshot"><a href="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/e8c9agw343.jpg"><img src="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/e8c9agw343.jpg" alt="Two asura wielding futuristic shields made of separate metal plates held together by glowing blue technology. " width="590" height="332" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-50935" /></a></p>
<h3>Black Lion Chest Update: Whimsical Seas</h3>
<p>Inside each chest, you&#8217;re guaranteed to find a redeemable Black Lion Statuette, a Black Lion Material Bag: Secrets of the Obscure, and two common items. You also have a chance to find something rarer in the fifth slot, including special items, glyphs, and skins from the Steel Lotus Weapon Collection and the Lorekeeper Weapon Collection.</p>
<p><strong>Exclusive Item: Toymaker&#8217;s Party Skiff Skin</strong></p>
<p>Embark on a nautical adventure alongside the cuddliest toys! Surround yourself with a crew of soft animal plushies to overcome any obstacle on the high seas.</p>
<h3>What&#8217;s in Stock</h3>
<p>Starting March 22 and continuing for the next few days, select minis will be 20% off, including the Mini Plush Aurene, Mini Fox Kit, Mini Angry Chest, Mini Snow Cougar Cub, and many more! Exploring Tyria is always more fun with a little friend!</p>
<h3>March Sales</h3>
<p>As part of our March sales, Black Lion Chest Keys will be 20% off from March 22 until March 26. In addition, all unique armor skins and chairs are 20% off starting today until March 26. Dazzle the masses with new armor combinations!</p>
<p class="screenshot"><a href="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/781f5Syn-Shield-Toy-08.jpg"><img src="//d3b4yo2b5lbfy.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/781f5Syn-Shield-Toy-08.jpg" alt="A character riding a colorful and playful boat filled with animal plushies and other childlike decorations." width="590" height="332" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-50935" /></a></p>
<li class="yui3-g">
<div class="yui3-u-1">
<h3>Available Now in the Gem Store!</h3>
<p>Log into <em>Guild Wars 2</em> and press 'O' to access the Black Lion Trading Company for these great offers and more!</p>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>